<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sammyjs on </title>
    <link>/tags/sammyjs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sammyjs on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sammyjs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating KnockoutJS and AngularJS – Part 1</title>
      <link>/2013-02-05-evaluating-knockoutjs-and-angularjs-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013-02-05-evaluating-knockoutjs-and-angularjs-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I stated in my earlier post &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jonathanchannon.com/2013/01/09/javascript-is-the-future-maybe/&#34; title=&#34;JavaScript is the future…maybe!&#34;&gt;“JavaScript is the future…maybe”&lt;/a&gt; so with that in mind I had to brush up my JS skills and get more involved with the language’s core concepts so after watching some videos and reading some articles I was ready to look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://knockoutjs.com&#34;&gt;KnockoutJS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://angularjs.org/&#34;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I actually looked at these two I spent some time with &lt;a href=&#34;http://sammyjs.org/&#34;&gt;SammyJS&lt;/a&gt; but realised afterwards it was mainly MVC based and not around 2-way binding that Knockout and Angular offer. However, I really liked it and it seemed very familiar and easy to use, the reason being it was inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sinatrarb.com/&#34;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt; which we all know &lt;a href=&#34;http://nancyfx.org/&#34;&gt;Nancy&lt;/a&gt; was also inspired by and we also know how much &lt;a href=&#34;http://nancyfx.org/mvm.html&#34;&gt;I like Nancy&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting to grips with any language or frameworks is tricky and the best way to do it is to write an application using it. The next difficult thing to overcome is an idea for writing an application. ToDo list’s are very common with JavaScript frameworks and there is a whole website for you to peruse but after looking at SammyJS and their docs they walk through writing a simple shopping basket so I thought I’d use that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating KnockoutJS and AngularJS – Part 2</title>
      <link>/2013-02-05-evaluating-knockoutjs-and-angularjs-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013-02-05-evaluating-knockoutjs-and-angularjs-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jonathanchannon.com/2013/02/05/evaluating-knockoutjs-and-angularjs-part-1/&#34; title=&#34;Evaluating KnockoutJS and AngularJS – Part 1&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt;, I described how I was using the demo tutorial from &lt;a href=&#34;http://sammyjs.org/&#34;&gt;SammyJS&lt;/a&gt; to get a better understanding of &lt;a href=&#34;http://angularjs.org/&#34;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://knockoutjs.com/&#34;&gt;KnockoutJS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post I will focus on what I found when using KnockoutJS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again if you just want to get to the code then feel free to take a look here for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jchannon/AngularShopping&#34;&gt;Angular&lt;/a&gt; and here for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jchannon/KnockoutShopping&#34;&gt;Knockout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;knockout&#34;&gt;Knockout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly Knockout should be commended on their documentation and online tutorials. Their website tutorials follows a step by step approach and once you have completed each step you can click through to the next section. You can also leave the tutorial and come back to it and it will remember where you left. There is great support in the KnockoutJS room in Jabbr and I’d like to thank &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/davepermen&#34;&gt;David Spörri&lt;/a&gt; for answering my newbie JS and Knockout questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>