<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>REST on </title>
    <link>/tags/rest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in REST on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rest/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Hypermedia client?</title>
      <link>/2016-04-28-what-is-a-hypermedia-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016-04-28-what-is-a-hypermedia-client/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in Hypermedia for quite a while.  I bugged &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/darrelmiller&#34;&gt;Darrel Miller&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/gblock&#34;&gt;Glenn Block&lt;/a&gt; (Glenn Miller) so much so they created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLbc9sDUxHqX60XJaTnNnKvI2mRighInDW&#34;&gt;YouTube show&lt;/a&gt; called &amp;ldquo;In The Mood for HTTP&amp;rdquo;.  I bought their book &lt;a href=&#34;http://webapibook.net/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Designing Evolvable Web APIs with ASP.NET&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, I am waiting for &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920037958.do&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;RESTful Web Clients Enabling Reuse Through Hypermedia&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/mamund&#34;&gt;Mike Amundsen&lt;/a&gt;, I have &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jonathanchannon.com/2015/08/07/hypermedia-and-nancyfx/index.html&#34;&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; about how to return different media types with NancyFX and I am looking at going to &lt;a href=&#34;http://2016.uk.restfest.org/&#34;&gt;restfest.org&lt;/a&gt; in Edinburgh this year, a REST conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing that I have always discussed with Glenn Miller is that there seems, or from my perception, that there is a lot of emphasis on the server returning media types(HAL,Siren,JSON-LD, Collection+Json) and very little information about hypermedia clients.  The information that I have come across which is very little, again coulkd be due to my lack of Google-fu, seems to generate a mis-conception.  The mis-conception I have come across is that if you have an API that returns hypermedia then your client should be able to magically work with it.  It should know everything that is required to browse the API and discover its way around.  I never quite grasped how that was supposed to happen and was serioulsy confused.  I had seen a video that showed when the server returned its responses, using Javascript it would loop over all the properties in the payload and then display them in a HTML page.  The emphasis was that if new bits of data were added then they would appear magically in the UI.  That seemed like a nice feature but I still didn&amp;rsquo;t quite get how it went from hitting the root of the API to finding its way into the guts of it.  The server would return links in the payload with &amp;ldquo;rels&amp;rdquo; and I was baffled how this magic client knew what to do with a rel or even how it knew what rels it would return.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NancyFX and Hypermedia</title>
      <link>/2015-08-07-hypermedia-and-nancyfx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015-08-07-hypermedia-and-nancyfx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been slowly educating my self on hypermedia; what it is, how does it help and how to use it.  I must say I&amp;rsquo;ve found it a very interesting topic and I thought it was time I put some information into a blog post just in case the 2 people that read this blog might find it useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my day job I&amp;rsquo;m responsible for a HTTP API (notice I didn&amp;rsquo;t use REST) and some months ago I spoke to Glenn Block around a general discussion about hypermedia.  Glenn put this on YouTube if you want to watch it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>