<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on </title>
    <link>/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/career/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why .Net should become independent!</title>
      <link>/2013-05-29-why-net-should-become-independent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013-05-29-why-net-should-become-independent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently changed jobs and as usual was at the mercy of recruitment agents. The advert for my job contained things like ASP.Net MVC, Entity Framework &amp;amp; TFS (luckily there were other cool pieces of technology on that list and what the role entailed interested me and once I had joined the company I saw they were open to other tech/approaches that made people’s workflow and output more beneficial to developers as well as the company. In fact I implemented an API written in &lt;a href=&#34;http://nancyfx.org/&#34;&gt;Nancy&lt;/a&gt; on my first day and paved the way for Git in the first week).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My point being that whenever I hear from recruiters or look for jobs all the adverts basically list the full Microsoft stack. I recently heard from a friend who runs his own company that he gave his CV to a recruitment agent and was basically rejected because his .Net experience was not MS based enough. I know his .Net skills are very good but because those .Net skills were put to good use using OSS projects he is unlikely to get a job in the mainstream .Net market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These adverts usually contain a list of tech/experience similar to: MVC, Webforms, Visual Studio, SQL Server, Entity Framework, WCF, LINQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; What’s the common denominator here?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; They are all owned by Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; What operating system do these all run on?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Microsoft Windows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; What framework and programming language do they run on?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Microsoft .Net and C#&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spot a pattern?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So lets point out the obvious, the operating system, the frameworks, the language, the tooling and the data storage are all owned and implemented by one company (and they say Apple tries to lock its users in).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Old Development Language Switcheroo</title>
      <link>/2013-04-02-the-old-development-language-switcheroo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013-04-02-the-old-development-language-switcheroo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a C# developer I think I’m pretty safe in saying that its not going away any time soon however, its my opinion that to not become irrelevant you need to have options. Some may argue that its better to be master of one than a Jack of all trades but lets just say you can’t find your next job in the primary language you want to work in. What do you do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have looked more into JavaScript recently and with that comes server and client scope for the use of the language so with some understanding of JS that would be probably the best bet for me however, as much as this may annoy some I think I actually prefer statically typed languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I know there is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.typescriptlang.org/&#34;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/a&gt; that I could use for my &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodejs.org/&#34;&gt;node.js&lt;/a&gt; apps but I see that as more of a workaround and not a core feature of JavaScript. I’m not saying anything bad against JS and the libraries/frameworks that I have used I like but I just find it easier to learn and know what I can do when I have decent intellisense showing me what I can do with my code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is OSS good for your career?</title>
      <link>/2012-09-25-is-oss-good-for-your-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012-09-25-is-oss-good-for-your-career/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got your attention? Good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me start by pointing out there are many opinions about the answer to this question. You will have yours and I have mine, that’s called freedom of speech. I would like to hear your opinions so leave it in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explain that I have had 4 jobs in the last 10-11 years. 3 of those were via recruitment agents. They check your skills, tick them off and pass you over to the employer if they match and hopefully you get an interview. That process has happened to me in each of those 3 times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have read my previous blog posts you’ll know I have spent the last year reading a lot of other peoples code and learning all the best practices I can in a bid to become a better software developer as well as give back to the developer community where I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending a couple of months porting &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jonathanchannon.com/2012/09/21/nancyfx-ravendb-nerddinner-and-me&#34;&gt;NerdDinner over to NancyFX&lt;/a&gt; I realised that I had not looked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asp.net/mvc&#34;&gt;ASP.Net MVC 4&lt;/a&gt; and the new features built into it. I felt slightly strange at that point as I was usually an early adopter of these things keen to check out the new stuff. I think this was partly due to the fact I had spent a lot of time learning &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nancyfx.org&#34;&gt;NancyFX&lt;/a&gt; and really quite enjoying the framework and interacting with the small community of people who use Nancy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>